[upbeat music playing]
[Jerry’s voice]
This is a 1977 Toyota FJ40 Land Cruiser
in mustard yellow
with a black vinyl interior.
The Land Cruiser.
“Built tough to get you there and back.”
I love that they tell you
they’re gonna get you back.
I’ve always liked these vehicles.
It’s basic, it’s classic, it’s durable,
it’s user-friendly.
I love the way this rear window
kinda curves around the back.
The wheels look like cut up paper plates.
It just seems like a giant toy.
It’s got a Tonka look about it.
Some people take the Toyota logo
and repaint it to say “Tonka.”
I like to imagine that I live in Africa,
and I’m doing important research,
and this is the only vehicle I’ve got
to get everywhere in Africa,
and you can’t break down,
because it’s Africa.
You know,
it’s got big wheels and high-cut fenders,
so that you can go anywhere
and do anything.
And even if you get stuck,
you got a winch to get out.
Hey, wait a minute. I am stuck.
Stop the opening.
-Let’s go. Come on.
-[Jerry laughing]
[Jerry’s voice]
This approachable, no-nonsense vibe…
This is you, isn’t it?
…reminded me of my very special guest
this week, Miss Ellen DeGeneres.
Who’s also so friendly, and accessible,
and real, and fun to be with.
[both sigh]
[Ellen on phone] Hello?
[Jerry on phone] Hello, Ellen.
[Ellen] Jerry, hi. I didn’t expect you.
[Jerry] What year do you think it was
that we last saw each other?
[Ellen] We played Ping-Pong
at the Comedy at the Hermosa Beach.
-[Jerry] Really?
-[Ellen] That’s what I remember.
-[Jerry] That’s a good memory.
-[Ellen] Looking forward to spending time.
-Haven’t seen you in ages.
-[Jerry] On my way.
I’m Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
[brake ratchets]
Wow.
-[Jerry] Isn’t it cool?
-[Ellen] Yes.
Oh, my God.
-It’s just got that “you” look.
-Fantastic.
-Have you been on safari?
-No.
-You should do a safari.
-Okay. Something else I gotta do.
[Ellen] I like that you put your
turn signal on from the driveway.
-I love driving, and that’s part of it.
-I see.
Your talk show, you can’t have imagined
that would be as successful as it’s been.
I don’t know. It’s so funny, because I…
I mean, I still don’t get it.
I still don’t get my appeal. You know?
-You don’t?
-No.
I mean, I really don’t.
Well, how the hell do you run all this,
if you don’t understand?
I just go along with it.
You know? It’s like “all right.”
What would you like your appeal to be?
What would you like people to think
when they see you?
I’m a good person. I’m a nice person.
-Nobody’s paying to see a nice person.
-You go right ahead.
-Really?
-No.
I was obsessed with comedians,
but I never thought
I was gonna be a comedian.
What was the hinge that it happened?
Someone asked me to do something
to help raise money,
and someone said:
“You get up onstage, and be funny.”
-So I got up onstage.
-Right.
I brought a bag, a Burger King Whopper,
and fries, and a shake.
And I started a sentence, I said,
“I’m so sorry. This is the first time I’ve
ever been onstage, and I’m so nervous,
so I didn’t eat all day,
and I realized that on the way over,
so I stopped to get this.
I hope you don’t mind.”
And then I started a sentence, saying,
“I don’t know if you’ve ever noticed,
but when people…” and then I took a bite.
And then I put my finger up, and said…
You know how people do that? Like,
why start a sentence, and then, you know.
-So I literally ate the entire…
-That’s funny.
I started the same sentence
over and over again,
and finished the entire Whopper and fries.
And then said:
“I’m so sorry, that’s my time.”
-That is a funny bit.
-That’s what I did for the first time.
And then I had to start writing material.
Then I had to, like, come up with ideas.
And then the thing that changed my life,
of course,
is my girlfriend was killed
in a car accident,
and I just kept thinking,
“Why is this 23-year-old girl
that I loved,
you know, just… gone?”
And I just thought, “What if we could
just pick up the phone, and call up God,
and ask these questions,
and have a conversation?”
’Cause people pray all the time,
but really,
wouldn’t it be amazing
if you could have a connection?
-Yeah.
-So, I literally started writing,
that it would ring for a long time.
I didn’t mean for it to be funny.
But I just thought it would ring
a long time. It’s big. It’s a big place.
And then finally, when God answers,
I’d be put on hold, like…
And then it’s “Onward, Christian
Soldiers”, but it’s not a tape, it’s live.
And I literally wrote it
without putting my pen down,
and I finished it, and I was like,
“Oh, my God,
I’m gonna do this on Johnny Carson,
and I’m gonna be the first woman
in the history of the show
to be called over
to sit down with Johnny Carson.”
And five years later, I was
the first woman in the history of the show
to sit down with Johnny Carson, and…
Because of the phone call to God.
-Wow.
-I know.
-Crazy.
Have you ever had
any other kinds of visions like that,
of things that were gonna happen,
that happened?
I think being…
famous was really important to me,
and I do believe that that intention
was set early on.
And I was raised Christian Science,
so nobody really acknowledged
-pain or anything, you know?
-Right.
There was very little
expression of emotions, or depth, or love.
-Oh, really?
-Yeah.
You know?
But my brother was famous before me.
My brother was on Saturday Night Live.
He was Mr. Hands for Mr. Bill.
-He was?
-Yeah. He helped create Mr. Bill.
Wow, I didn’t know that.
[Ellen] You’re an excellent driver.
Thank you.
That’s one of my favorite compliments.
Not one crunch or anything.
-Not one “krrg.”
-Thank you.
-What do you need?
-My wallet.
Losing your wallet is the scariest thing.
I don’t have a wallet.
I just keep it loose.
I just keep the cash loose in my pants.
“Loose in my pants,”
that’s the Louisiana coming out.
Yeah. “Y’all” and “loose in my pants.”
I don’t know that I’ve used that statement
before, “loose in my pants.”
I like it loose in my pants.
[laughs] Well, that may be
the name of my special.
[laughs]
-Hi, how are you? Good to see you.
-Hi, how are you?
-[Jerry] Do you like coffee?
-[Ellen] I do.
-I bet you want coffee.
-I would love a coffee, yes.
When I lost my sitcom,
I didn’t work for three years solid.
Until I got the show, until the talk show.
Right. So when you say
you weren’t working, what were you doing?
I was in Ojai,
like, literally bitter and sad
and angry and… You know?
Like, how,
like, did this change everything,
just by me being honest
and saying I’m gay?
Like, why is this such a shock to people?
-And why is it such a big deal?
-Uh-huh.
But literally, I went on tour, and I would
say 90 percent of the audience was gay.
And some brave straight people went.
And all the gay people really thought
I was doing some kind of gay pride tour.
Right, right.
So I was making fun of the fact
that I was their leader now.
And I was like, “I am not your leader.
I’m not anybody’s leader.”
I act like that around firemen.
-I love firemen.
-Firemen are very exciting to see.
A fireman stopped me the other day,
I got so excited to talk to him.
They’re great. They don’t carry guns.
They run into danger.
And they get a lot of girls too,
don’t they?
-Do they?
-I think so.
They had that calendar.
I know you don’t like penises,
but even if you did…
I’m not saying I don’t.
-You don’t?
-It’s not that I don’t.
You don’t? You don’t.
-Or you do?
-Well, they’re fine. I don’t have a…
That’s how I feel about it.
Purely aesthetics.
The penis, it’s…
It has a function.
-It’s clever in the way it works.
-Yes.
It’s kinda like one of these
expandable strollers.
Right.
Because the world is such a scary place
right now, like, in so many ways.
And you have children,
and there’s North Korea,
and there’s fires, there’s storms…
It just overwhelms me with, like, dread.
-Like, do you go to those places?
-No.
-You don’t?
You know, my attitude is
that each generation kinda gets this thing
dumped in your lap to deal with.
Right. If I talk to your kids,
when I meet them,
I’ll ask them what they think.
I don’t really care what they think.
See? That’s my point.
You chose to bring them into this world,
so it’s your job to…
You say “chose.” I was just
fooling around like everybody else, okay?
-So let’s not put it all on me.
-Okay.
-It’s a lot of fun.
-Yeah.
-Having kids?
-Yeah. It’s a lot of fun.
If you look at it as I do,
without any sense of responsibility.
Exactly.
What do you think of this theory?
I think you’re clearly
a very empathetic person.
Yes.
Do you think the size of people’s eyes
has something to do with
how aware and sensitive they are?
I know that I have large ears.
Racist people always have little eyes,
little mouths, not taking in a lot.
-Really?
-What do you think of that theory?
Well, first of all,
I feel better about my ears now.
Are you at all upset at this point of
what you wore on your first Tonight Show?
You know who guided me?
And that was a big mistake. Sinbad.
-And I was following Sinbad’s advice.
-[Jerry laughs]
That’s how insecure I was.
All these other things you do,
I can’t do any of them.
You could be a talk show host tomorrow.
I can’t do it.
-Yes, you can.
-I can’t talk. No.
I can’t talk
to people I’m not interested in.
You could do, like, six a year,
or something.
That’s what I’m doing.
-I like a lot of the Netflix stuff.
-Right.
And now they don’t even give you time
to make a decision. You’re watching one…
It used to be, like, 12 seconds,
and now it’s like four seconds,
-and it goes right to the next one.
-Right.
It’s like feeding a goose pâté.
You know the way they make pâté?
It’s a horrible thing to think about.
-What they do to gooses?
-Yeah.
-It’s horrible.
-Yes.
That’s what I feel like it is.
By the way, they don’t feed them pâté.
No, they make pâté…
-From overfeeding them.
-It’s horrible.
-It’s the cruelest thing ever.
-Yeah.
-I hope you’re happy.
-Just think about them feeding ’em pâté.
-Because that’s even crueler.
-Yeah.
We’re now gonna give you
the food you’re gonna be.
This is delicious.
So, you mean Nancy,
who used to be next door to me…
Right.
Oh, God.
You people are horrible.
Yep. Human beings are horrible.
They’re horrible, but
the problem with human beings
is as much as you may want
to dislike or disapprove of them,
then they just do one wonderful thing.
And they get you back in again.
It’s an abusive relationship we have here.
-With our own species.
-Right.
We keep believing
they’re gonna stop doing this, right?
He’s not gonna beat me again.
Wow.
-Right? How do you like this premise?
-Yeah.
So we go from pâté
to someone beating their wife.
-Yes.
-Yeah.
-You know that’s how they do it.
He is an abusive husband,
but then he’s so nice.
-He’s like “Hey, here, have some pâté.”
-Yeah. Have some pâté.
And now we’re calling it “pah-tay.”
It’s turned into “pah-tay.”
If you did smoke,
what brand would you like?
Maybe a Parliament.
Oh, really? With the quarter inch…?
-The recessed filter?
-Yeah.
Do you miss cigarette advertising
on TV at all?
No, I don’t miss it.
-I do.
-Really?
I just like that it was an interesting
problem that they had to solve.
To make these people look like fun people
I wanna be, but they’re smokers.
Which is so gross.
-Right.
-But we’re gonna put them on a sailboat,
and we’re gonna dress them
in a blue stripe.
With, you know, little white shorts.
-That would be Salem.
-Salem.
I’ve never seen anyone drink
so much coffee in my entire life.
It’s too much. It doesn’t affect you?
Of course it affects me.
See how fast…
Wow.
I thought I would have kids. When I was
younger I really wanted to have a baby.
I thought I would adopt.
I never thought I would have a baby,
but I thought I would want kids.
-You still could.
-No, Portia doesn’t want kids.
She doesn’t like the squealing
when they’re in a pool.
That high-pitched squealing of joy
that they have.
-She doesn’t like that.
-All right.
But she wants lots more horses,
which I don’t.
Right. What does that got to do with you?
Well, you know. It’s a lot of horses.
-You don’t have to take care of them.
-No.
Do you want my advice?
No… Okay.
-Anyways, yeah.
-That was a great delivery.
You included the “no” in the “yes.”
-That’s why it was so funny.
-I know.
My advice…
-I’m not gonna say “pah-tay.”
-Uh-uh.
My advice is just keep giving her horses,
until she can’t stand them.
Okay. That’s not okay. Really?
-It’s my general wife advice anyway.
-All right.
Always give a wife whatever she wants.
She will eventually see.
“I didn’t really want that.”
-You know she doesn’t want it.
-Right.
-Let them find out on their own.
-Okay.
-Do you have cats and dogs?
-Two cats, two dogs.
-What kind of dogs?
-Dachshunds.
-They’re cute.
-Stupid.
-Are they?
-Very stupid.
-Did you get them both at the same time?
-No.
So you knew it was like that,
and got a second one?
-I don’t do anything.
-I see. Okay.
-You know how you have favorites?
-Yeah.
You don’t feel as bad about that
with animals.
-You don’t wanna do that with kids.
But I’m sure you do.
I mean, you’ve gotta have a favorite kid.
-No.
-You have to.
No, you really don’t.
-They’re all different. I know that.
-Yeah, of course.
You know, love is not rational.
You could say,
“Well, I love this person, because…”
But that’s not really the reason.
There is no reason. You just… You feel it.
-And you have no control over it.
-No, and you have no control over it.
Which is a weird thing, because that’s why
I think people get themselves into trouble
in relationships with people that,
as you said, beat them.
-Like, you…
-Yes.
What do you mean, “as I said”?
They do beat them.
-Are they funny?
-Yeah.
-Who’s the funniest?
-I am.
-Let’s go on a tour.
-Let’s go.
All right.
Yeah. Have one more sip of your coffee.
Wow. I mean…
You’re looking at me like I got
a bent spoon here and I’m heating it up.
It’s the irony of if you die
from too much coffee.
-Who cares?
-This is your show.
Haven’t we have enough
of whatever the hell I do?
-Come on. It’s enough.
-No, we don’t wanna lose you.
You’re sweet.
[Jerry] That’s Jane Fonda.
-What kind is it?
-It’s a Ferrari 250.
[no audible speech]
-I like drug stores.
-Yeah, me too.
How about this? You wanna feel like that?
-What? Yes.
-I don’t think I wanna feel like that.
-I don’t like…
-You don’t have Jean Naté?
The only ladies that live around here…
-It’s an old lady…
-I know.
-I would think it’d be here.
-It’s not an old lady place.
Don’t act like where I live
is an old lady…
There’s a lot of young people
who live here.
Look at all these people.
They’re all young.
No, they’re not.
I don’t have enough.
Don’t you anticipate when you shoot these
things you’re gonna spend money?
No. I told you, I anticipate nothing.
I don’t care what happens.
I’ll deal with it when it happens.
You’re right.
There’s no older people here.
No older people at all. It’s all kids.
-Hey, where’s the keys?
-I don’t know.
Do you ever get nervous about
people scratching your car, or anything?
-No.
-Actually you do,
because my friend Nacho said
he was driving with you…
That’s different.
The keys are not in the car.
See, I told you
you shouldn’t leave the keys in the car.
-Looking for a key.
-I didn’t touch ’em.
I didn’t either.
-You didn’t put ’em in your pocket?
-Maybe I did, but I don’t…
I must have. But I don’t have them.
I swear.
They’re not in…
It was to teach you a lesson.
And you should always…
I could’ve let that go longer.
If you had any balls.
Which you don’t.
I should’ve let it go really, really long.
I don’t think it was going anyplace funny.
-Had we gone longer…
-How’d you get them out? How’d you do it?
When you walked around the car.
That’s funny.
You just said it wasn’t funny.
No, the way you did it is funny.
What you did is not funny.
Everyone is so friendly here,
and you never hear helicopters,
you never hear sirens.
-It’s so great.
-I’m so glad you like it.
That sounded sarcastic.
A little bit.
-This thing is cool, isn’t it?
-Yeah.
’Cause usually there’s the vents up here.
And there’s a thing
where you could even open it.
-[man] I love you!
-[Ellen laughs]
Him or me?
[hollers, indistinct]
Both of us, I think.
Sorry you had to turn.
[Jerry] Can you imagine how irresistible
it would have been
for somebody like me to have met…
’Cause I didn’t even know
people were named Portia.
Met a girl named Portia.
You know what that would’ve done to me?
-You would’ve married her.
-Yeah.
But then she wouldn’t wanna marry you.
No. The other name…
Alec Baldwin’s wife’s name is Hilaria.
Which I thought…
-Is that right?
-Yeah.
I didn’t know that.
I thought,
what a great name for a comedian’s wife.
-Yes.
-“Hilaria.”